Sri Chandra Dronavalli

Denton, TX 76205 | 469.925.8261 | dsrichandra77@gmail.com github.com/dronavallisrichandra | www.linkedin.com/in/dronavalli-sri-chandra/

CAREER SUMMARY

Data Science graduate student at the University of North Texas graduating in May 2024. Seeking a Research / Internship opportunity as Data Scientist/ Machine Learning Engineer focussed on analyzing large datasets and modeling the ML Algorithms for creating impact in business by data visualizations. Superb attention to detail, highly skilled in Python, R, data wrangling, SQL, data analytics, data visualization, Big Data, and machine learning with 6 years of experience as a Software Engineer.

EDUCATION

University of North Texas | Denton, TX Expected: May 2024

Master of Science, Data Science GPA: 3.8

Relevant Course Work: Data Visualization, Data Analytics, Data Science techniques, Machine Learning, Data Mining

Prasad V. Potluri Siddhartha Institute of Technology | Vijayawada May 2017

Bachelor of Technology: Electronics and Computer Engineering GPA: 3.42

Skills

Languages: C#, Python, R, SQL, PL/SQL, PowerShell

MicroController: Raspberry Pi Frameworks: MVC, Web API

Databases: MySQL

Bigdata Ecosystems: Hadoop, HDFS, HBase, Hive, Spark, Kafka

Data Visualizations: Tableau **Cloud technologies:** AWS, GCP

NO SQL Databases: Cassandra, MongoDB

Development Methodologies: Agile/Scrum, Waterfall

Version Controls: Git, SVM, GitHub

ETL Tools: SSIS

Reporting Tools: MS Office (Word/Excel/PowerPoint/ Visio/Outlook), SSRS

Operating Systems: All versions of UNIX, Windows, LINUX

Automation and CI/CD tools Jenkins, Docker, Git

Machine Learning Algorithms: Linear Regression, Random Forest, Naive Bayesian, Decision Tree, Support Vector

Machine, K-Mean, KNN, Neural Network.

Deep Learning: Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), Artificial Neural Network (ANN).

Statistics: Descriptive Statistics, Probability Theory, Time Series Analysis, Bayesian statistics.

Soft Skills: Self-motivated, Organized, Time Management, Independent and Flexible.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

IOT-Based Irrigation Controller

> The aim of this work is to develop a smart irrigation monitoring system using raspberry pi. The focus area will be parameters such as soil moisture, temperature, and humidity. This system will be a substitute for traditional farming methods.

Comcast Telecom Consumer Complaints Analysis

Used Python libraries such as NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, and matplotlib to complete the given analysis and visualization tasks.

Mercedes Benz Greener Manufacturing

> Used Python libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, seaborn, and XG Boost to predict the time it takes to pass testing.

Data Science Capstone Healthcare

Used Python libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, seaborn, matplotlib, Logistic Regression, ROC Curve, Decision Tree Classifier, Random Forest, Support Vector Classifier, and K-NN to predict if the patients in the dataset have diabetes or not.

Walmart Sales Prediction

- Implemented a model to Predict the sales using NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, seaborn, matplotlib, Regression models to evaluate the performance and accuracy using MSE & RMSE.
- Created innovative sheets, dashboards, and stories to give the insights for the stores data using Tableau, developed machinemodels with the perfect fit to predict the future sales.

Multimodal Machine Learning for Detecting and Classifying Brain Tumors Using MRI Scans

May 2023—Present

Trying to implement the detection and classifying the brain tumours in data centric programming like Python and using their Libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, matplotlib, and TensorFlow still in the process of data cleaning and research.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Vertex Computer Systems Hyderabad, India Role: Software Engineer Dec 2020 - Jul 2022

Responsibilities:

- Data wrangling to clean, transform, and reshape the data utilizing Python library Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, SciPy, matplotlib, sci-kit-learn)
- Developed Powershell scripts in JAMS for client API Integration for Faster Data Accessing.
- Involved in the entire data science project life cycle and actively involved in all the phases including data extraction, data cleaning, statistical modelling, and data visualization with large data sets of structured and unstructured data.
- Skilled in Advanced Regression Modelling, Correlation, Multivariate Analysis, Model Building, Business Intelligence tools and application of Statistical Concepts.
- Automated recurring reports using SQL and Python and visualized them on BI platforms like Tableau.
- Updating the stakeholders with the improvements made in automating the tasks.
- Managing the workflow and pipeline through Airflow.
- Used **Jenkins** for data science projects for automating tasks such as data collection, preprocessing, and model training.
- Used docker to create reproducible environments for the data science projects by specifying the exact versions of software packages and libraries for the project, so it can run consistently across different computing environments.
- Moved 500+ manual jobs to JAMS.
- Worked with datasets of varying degrees of size and complexity including both structured and unstructured data.
- Optimised the Powershell scripts to run less than a 1min.
- Implemented SQL Scripts to extract reports with analytics with exact figures.
- Reduced the run/ threads created for each job from 1000+ to less than 100 counts.

Environment: Python, SQL, Powershell, SSIS, JAMS, File Zilla, SAP, Tableau, Airflow.

BrandMuscle India Pvt Ltd	Apr 2019 - Dec 2020
Bengaluru, India	
Role: Software Engineer 2	

Responsibilities:

- Coordinated with the Business Analyst team to evaluate and improve the Performance of the Channel Builder by query optimization.
- Modified existing logic to correct coding errors and handle Unhandled exceptions, upgrade interfaces and improve overall performance.
- Rapidly improved the performance of the Checkout flow from 8000ms to 2000ms for a larger amount of orders and integration feasibility into existing systems.
- Supervised the Support team for various enhancements and bugs and made recommendations to improve order issues by 9%.

Environment: Web API, Angular, SQL, Mongo DB, JAMS, Camunda, File Zilla, Azure Blob storage, JIRA, DevOps, Umbraco, Kibana

BrandMuscle India Pvt Ltd	Sep 2017 – May 2019
Bengaluru, India	
Role: Software Engineer 1	

Responsibilities:

- Led JAMS development initiative as Subject Matter Expert and primary point-of-contact for project management staff for implementing the Automated SQL Scripts through JAMS with a Throughput of resources by 50%.
- Researched, designed, and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval, and indexing has increased the data retrieval speed by 22%
- Major key Resource for the Migration of Windows Task Scheduler and Task Scheduler Jobs to JAMS as well as various SSIS jobs that are used for Clients by using a third-party application- JAMS has improved the monitoring.
- Developed Powershell scripts in JAMS for client API Integration for Faster Data Accessing and Injection to Database
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded client expectations.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans.
- Developed and optimized SQL stored procedures to load user and location data provided by the client in CSV/TXT format into the Database according to client specifications.
- Implemented the Major Enhancement in Location Builder to trigger the mails using the SMTP host.

Environment: C#, .Net MVC, SQL, Powershell, SSIS, JAMS, File Zilla, Azure Blob storage, JIRA, DevOps

CERTIFICATIONS

Master's Program - Data Scientist: Simplilearn Certified in collaboration with IBM

Aug 2021

- Data Science with Python, R
- Advance Machine Learning
- Tableau 10

- Big Data Hadoop & Spark Developer
- Data Science Capstone

COMPETITIONS

Prediction Competition – Bike Sharing Demand – 3rd position

Nov 2022

I have always been passionate about ML Models and entered this competition to have a professional critique of my work. I was able to improve my Modelling skills and learned more about the use of techniques that improves accuracy. I placed third out of 27 teams by a score of 48.41668.

https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/info5502-bike-sharing-demand

Regression Competition – Data Rush: UNT's Ultimate Regression Challenge – 2nd position

Mar 2023

In this competition, we are using Machine learning models to Predict the body fat percentage using regression techniques. Predicting body fat percentage can be an important part of a person's health profile, as it is linked to various health risks such as heart disease, diabetes, and high blood pressure. By accurately predicting body fat percentage, healthcare providers can make informed decisions about patients' health and provide tailored treatment plans to help manage their health risks.

https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/data-rush-unts-ultimate-regression-challenge

STUDENT ORGANIZATIONS

STODERT ORGANIZATIONS	
Indian Student Association (ISA)	Aug 2022 - Present
Data Science Organization	Jun 2022 - Present
ACCOMPLISHMENTS	
Star Performer Award	Jun 2019 – Sep 2019
Star Performer Award	Sep 2019 – Dec 2019